Guide to the Rwanda Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Rwanda collection
1953-2010
MS 1536
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.27
(7 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material and ephemera relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Rwanda.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in this collection is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material and ephemera relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Rwanda.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Rwanda -- Description and travel; Rwanda -- Economic conditions; Rwanda -- Politics and government
- Inventory
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, [1953?]-1958, [1983?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - L'Administration du Ruanda-Urundi: territoire sous tutelle de la Belgique, Ministère des Affaires Etrangères et du Commerce Extérieur de la Belgique, 1955 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Government papers: speeches, treaties, documents, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Actualités Nationales et Internationales: bulletin quotidien de l'Agence Rwandaise de Presse (ARP), 1975, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Periodicals: newspapers, magazines, 1977-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student organizations: political/literary journals, written materials, 1978-1982, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Communauté Economique des Pays des Grands Lacs (C.E.P.G.L.): journal, 1980 April (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ministère de la Défense Nationale: military journals, 1980-1981, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural journal, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Political journals, 1990-[1993?] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Quatre Années de Vie: 1986-1990: publication du Réseau des Femmes Oeuvrant pour le Développement Rural, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, Accession 1995-M-197
  - Additional printed materials, 1960, 1985, 1992-1996 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 2000-M-031
  - Additional printed materials, 1988, 1991-1997, 2000, undated (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 2006-M-032
  - L'ère de Liberté, no. 22, 1996 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Goboka," no. 006, 1996 March (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Hobe", 1982, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Ihuliro," no. 39, [1983] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Inganzo Y'umulilimbyi," AMR (Association des Musiciens du Rwanda), 1984 September (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Inkingi", undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Intambwe," vol. 14, no. 1; vol. 15, nos. 2-3, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Muyobozi," no. 1, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Le Rayon," no. 17, 1986 June (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Rwanda, Pays des Milles Collines," travel brochure, 1986 December (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Umunyamuryango (le coopérateur), 1984 November-December (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Umunyarwandakazi, publication of "L'Année Internationale pour la Femme, 1975 November-December (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, 1960-2006; Accession 2010-M-114
  Arrangement
  The material is arranged as received.
  - (Parc National Des Volcans:Conservation De La Nature Au Rwanda), Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ingabo, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Intego(special impunzi), Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ukuri (Numero sipesiyale: genoside mata 1994), 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Le Tribun du Peuple, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ijwi Ry'abakozi, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda case documents from Arusha, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Institute des Sciences Agronomiques du Rwanda (I.S.A.R.): Note Technique de Vulgarisation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1965-2000s; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material and keychain, 1965-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Posters, Circa 2000s (Folder 2)